Contact

6393842822 (Mobile) peter.ufondu@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/peter-ufondu-43a085160 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Analytical Skills Data Analysis Data Analytics

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Data Analysis with Python Verified International Academic Qualifications

Data Analysis Using Python Advanced ServiceNow for Fulfillers Certificate of Quantum Excellence

Publications

Importance of self interaction error removal in density functional calculations on water cluster anions

Study of water cluster anions using the self-interaction corrected density functional approximations

Electron Binding Energy Of Polar Molecules Using Fermi Löwdin Orbital Self Interaction Corrected Density Functional Scheme

Investigating the electronic properties of novel titanium oxonitridophosphate, Ti5P12N24O2, through structural distortions at the titanium sites

Vertical detachment energies of ammonia cluster anions using selfinteraction-corrected methods

Peter Ufondu

NERSC-CREATE to INSPIRE Research Fellow

Saskatoon, Saskatchewan, Canada

Summary

Motivated by a robust background in research, analytics, and data analysis honed through diverse roles within academia and the tech industry, I have developed a keen ability to navigate complex analytical challenges. My journey has not only sharpened my skills but also enriched my understanding of critical concepts in these areas. Currently, I am a Ph.D. student in the department of Physics and engineering Physics at the University of Saskatchewan, I am deeply engaged in pioneering research aimed at exploring the electronic properties of advanced materials. This involves a focused study on the distortion at the transition metal site, utilizing advanced Resonant Inelastic X-ray Scattering (RIXS) techniques. My commitment to excellence and continuous learning propels me to explore new frontiers in physics and technology.

Experience

University of Saskatchewan Doctorate Research Assistant September 2021 - Present (2 years 8 months) Saskatchewan, Canada

Applying Resonant Inelastic X-ray Scattering Techniques to Study Effect of Symmetry Distortion in Advanced Materials.

The University of Texas at El Paso
Graduate Research And Teaching Assistant
August 2018 - August 2021 (3 years 1 month)

El Paso, Texas Area

Studying weakly bound anionic molecules using self-interaction corrected DFT.

Quequest Technologies Limited Information Technology System Analyst July 2010 - December 2017 (7 years 6 months)

Lagos, Nigeria

Implement best practices IofTs for scalability, supportability, ease of maintenance, and system performance.

Education

University of Saskatchewan

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Physics · (September 2021 - December 2024)

The University of Texas at El Paso

Master of Science - MS, Computational Science · (2019 - 2021)

The University of Texas at El Paso

Master of Science - MS, Physics · (2018 - 2019)

Federal University of Technology Owerri Nigeria

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Physics · (2004 - 2009)